# Will Webberley

40 Planet Street, Cardiff, CF24 0HZ

⑤ 07787 567865

☑ will@flyingsparx.net

☐ flyingsparx.net

in flyingsparx

Data, software systems, development, and the web

I am extremely passionate in the field of technology and development with a natural flair for creating quality systems for a wide range of uses and users. I'm always excited to learn about new technologies from others and through self-taught means. I am a skilled communicator with expertise in working in distributed and multi-disciplinary teams and I enjoy conveying thoughts and ideas through presentations, talks, and discussions.

# Skillset

I'm highly proficient in and frequently use a wide range of languages, frameworks, and platforms.

#### Languages

Proficient Python, JAVA, PHP, Go, JavaScript, Shell, SQL, LATEX, HTML & CSS

Intermediate Perl, Ruby, C, C++

Platforms, Technologies, Techniques, and Frameworks

Proficient Git, Android dev., GNU/Linux & UNIX-like systems, Flask, Meteor & Node.js, MongoDB &

CouchDB, jQuery & AngularJS, WebSocket, Weka, Heroku, AWS, Nginx, Vim, Eclipse/NetBeans

Intermediate Django, Rails, iOS dev.

I am very experienced with and have expertise in writing and consuming various web-based APIs, and working in object-oriented and test-driven environments for platforms ranging from distributed servers to desktop and mobile.

# Recent Experience & Employment

2015–2017 Simply Do Ideas, Chief Technology Officer, Cardiff, UK.

Technical lead on and responsibility for company products.

2015 Chaser Technologies, Software Engineer, London, UK.

Building and maintaining Chaser systems, databases, APIs, and apps. I also led the data analysis processes managing large financial datasets.

2013-Present Cardiff University, Research Associate and Lecturer, Cardiff, UK.

**Research** as part of the International Technology Alliance (ITA) coalition between the UK MoD and the US Army Research Labs. I worked with a variety of US and UK academic and industry partners, such as IBM and Boeing, in advancing information and network sciences.

**Lecturer** of postgraduate masters (MSc Advanced Computer Science) students as module leader of Web and Social Computing, and two Computer Science undergraduate courses - Human-Computer Interaction (as module leader of  $\sim$ 140 students), and Algorithms & Data Structures.

I received consistently good feedback from peers and students, both in terms of technical knowledge and in style & approach. I was responsible for developing course materials, syllabae, exams, and coursework.

2010–2013 Cardiff University, Tutor and student supervisor, Cardiff, UK.

Tutoring, supervision, and assessment of BSc and MSc students in practical and theory-based sessions covering a variety of topics ranging from theory, mobile systems, heuristics, algorithms, and general programming.

**Examples of projects supervised:** Social media visualisation toolkits, digital asset stores.

# Education

# 2010–2014 PhD Computer Science, Cardiff University,

"Inferring Interestingness in Online Social Networks".

Exploring information propagation in online social networks. In particular, the use of Bayesian machine learning methodologies in the prediction of tweet popularity in Twitter as a basis for the inference and ranking of interesting user-contributed data.

I have periodically published interesting findings and analyses in proceedings, and have contributed to the "excellent"-rated EU Recognition project.

2007–2010 **BSc Computer Science**, *Cardiff University*, First-class honours.

# Community Involvement, Contribution & Output

Projects Examples of projects worked-on in spare time or in freelance:

- WekaPy & WekaGo Python and Go wrappers for the Weka machine-learning toolkit
- Gower Tides Native Android & iOS apps showing tidal events & surf/weather forecasts
- CENode Support human-machine and machine-machine communication at the network edge, working with Cardiff University and IBM UK

For more, please see github.com/flyingsparx and flyingsparx.net/project.

# peer-reviewed publications

- First-author "Retweeting beyond Expectation: Inferring Interestingness in Twitter", W.M. Webberley, S.M. Allen, R.M. Whitaker, under review for the journal of Computer Communications: Special Issue on Online Social Networks. 2015.
  - o "Inferring the Interesting Tweets in Your Network", W.M. Webberley, S.M. Allen, R.M. Whitaker, in Third International Conference on Cloud and Green Computing. Karsruhe, Germany, 2013.
  - "Retweeting: A Study of Message-Forwarding in Twitter", W.M. Webberley, S.M. Allen, R.M. Whitaker, in Workshop on Mobile and Online Social Networks, 2011. Milan, Italy, 2011.

For more, please see scholar.google.com/citations?user=b2RThHcAAAAJ.

- Written Invited articles for the Heroku Dev Center:
  - "Direct-to-S3 File Uploads in Node.js", Heroku 2014
  - "Direct-to-S3 File Uploads in Python", Heroku 2013
  - I aso maintain an active blog, which is hosted on my website at flyingsparx.net/blog.

### Spoken • Examples of informal talks given

- "Writing Useful Web APIs", 2015
- "Contributing to the Open-Source World", 2014
- "The Flask Microframework", 2013
- "Node.js: An Introduction to Development", 2012
- "Typesetting with LATEX", 2012
- "Developing Google Chrome Extensions", 2011

## • Examples of formal and academic talks and seminars given

- "Inferring Interestingness in OSNs" Guest speaker at King's College, London, 2014
- "Inferring the Interesting Tweets in Your Network", SOCIETY2.0, Karlsruhe, Germany, 2013
- "Finishing a PhD in Under 4 Years", Cardiff University Research Retreat, 2013
- "Weka the Machine-Learning Toolkit", Cardiff University MobiSoc Research Group, 2013
- "Retweeting: A Study of Message-Forwarding in Twitter", MOSN'11, Milan, Italy, 2011

Events I have taken part in and helped organised several community events, such as talks, seminar series, and hackathons.

#### Notes

A digital version of my CV is available in colour at flyingsparx.net/cv.pdf. The source code for my CV is available at github.com/flyingsparx/cv.